Inventory of the Benjamin Stoddert Ewell Papers 1784-1934
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Letters, 1784-1934. (Folder 1-19)
  - Letters: E, 1784-1934 (Folder 3-10)
    - Letters from Benjamin S. Ewell, April 1830-May 1898., 112 items. (Folder 3-5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.) to Richard Ewell, 29 November 1865. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 5 March 1866. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, March-May 1866., 3 items. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 7 March 1866. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 2 April 1866. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 3 May 1866. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to General Richard S. Ewell, 2 May 1866. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Rev. M. D. Hoge, 3 May 1866. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, 8 July 1866. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Mrs. L. C. Ewell, 13 August 1866. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Gen. Richard S. Ewell, 29 August 1866. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his daughter, Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Baltimore, Maryland, 7 November 1866. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 19 February 1867. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Gen. Richard S. Ewell, 22 April 1867. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Mrs. L. C. Ewell, 23 July 1867. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, 9 August 1867. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 28 August 1867. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his daughter, Elizabeth S. Ewell, 9 September 1867. (Folder 4)
        Enclosures: Letter from Beverly S. Scott, Jr., at Prince Edward Court House, to Col. Benjamin S. Ewell. 5 September 1867. Letter from Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Beverly S. Scott. 9 September 1867.
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, 18 September 1867. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, 7 October 1867. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to General Richard S. Ewell, 18 November 1867. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 6 December 1867. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his daughter, Elizabeth Ewell Scott, 23 December 1867. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.) to Mrs. L. C. Ewell, 1 January 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at New York, to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, 4 January 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, January 1868., 2 items. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 10 January 1868. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 28 January 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.) to Gen. Richard S. Ewell, 8 January 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., January-February 1868., 2 items. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 29 January 1868. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 17 February 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, 18 February 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 3 March 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, 11 March 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., May-June 1868., 3 items. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 8 May 1868. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 22 May 1868. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 18 June 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, 22 July 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Mrs. L. C. Ewell, 22 July 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Gen. Richard S. Ewell, 24 June 1868. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at New York, to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, 16 January 1869. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Gen. Henry A. Wise, 18 February 1869. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to General Richard S. Ewell, 18 June 1869. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 5 July 1869. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, 18 August 1869. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., January 1870-February 1871., 4 items. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 22 January 1870. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 13 April 1870. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 21 November 1870. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 26 February 1871. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Mrs. L. C. Ewell, 7 September 1870. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Mrs. L. C. Ewell, 14 September 1870. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Mrs. L. C. Ewell, 5 October 1870. (Folder 4)
        Enclosing letter from Charles McCulloch to Benjamin S. Ewell. 3 October 1870.
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.) to Mrs. L. C. Ewell, 26 October 1870. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.) to General Richard S. Ewell, 16 March 1871. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Mrs. L. C. Ewell, 29 March 1871. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, July-September 1871., 3 items. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 12 July 1871. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 4 August 1871. (Folder 4)
        - Letter, 16 September 1871. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.) to General Richard S. Ewell, 28 July 1871. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to General Richard S. Ewell, 19 August 1871. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 22 November 1871. (Folder 4)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Washington, D.C., to Charles W. Porter, 16 February 1872. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, 19 March 1872. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 2 May 1872. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to the public, 18 May 1872. (Folder 5)
        The South and Grant, from the Daily Morning Chronicle, Washington, 20 May 1872.
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, June 1872- May 1873., 3 items. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 21 June 1872. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 6 November 1872. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 22 May 1873. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 21 June 1873. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, July 1873-October 1874., 3 items. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 17 July 1873. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 25 September 1873. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 21 October 1874. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., November-December 1874., 3 items. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 25 November 1874. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 6 December 1874. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 16 December 1874. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, 12 August 1875. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to his sister, Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 23 January 1876. (Folder 5)
        Enclosures: Two designs for a cemetery monument.
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, May-June 1876., 2 items. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 18 May 1876. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 11 June 1876. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 10 August 1876. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Mrs. L. C. Ewell, 25 October 1876. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, 17 October 1876. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, July-November 1877., 2 items. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 19 July 1877. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 19 November 1877. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 1 August 1880. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, 11 August 1880. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., February-August 1883., 3 items. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 5 February 1883. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 21 May 1883. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 9 August 1883. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Bessie L. Scott, 21 August 1884. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Col. Thomas Tasker Gantt, 17 August 1885. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, February 1886-May 1887., 2 items. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 10 February 1886. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 23 May 1887. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at West Washington, D.C., 4 June 1887. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, August-December 1887., 2 items. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 1 August 1887. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 5 December 1887. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth Stoddert Ewell, at West Washington, D.C., 25 January 1888. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Ewell, James City County, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, 18 July 1889. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at Ewell, James City County, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., March-December 1892., 3 items. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 31 March 1892. (Folder 5)
        - Letter, 15 August 1892. (Folder 5)
          Enclosure: A letter from J. H. Richards, at Georgetown College, West Washington, D.C., to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C. 29 April 1892.
        - Letter, 6 December 1892. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (B. S.) to Paul H. Ewell, at Washington, D.C. Postmarked West Point, New York. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.) to Rebecca Ewell, at Bladensburg, Prince George's County, Maryland. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.) to Rebecca Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia Postmarked West Point, New York. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.), at West Point, New York to Rebecca Ewell, at Greenwich, Prince William County, Virginia. (Folder 5)
      - Ewell (Benjamin S.) to Mrs. L. C. Ewell. (Folder 5)
    - Ewell (Charlotte), at Dumfries, Prince William County, Virginia, to Tommy [ ? ], 6 September 1803. (Folder 6)
    - Ewell (D. L.), at Greenville, Virginia, to Richard S. Ewell, 3 September 1866. (Folder 6)
    - Ewell (Eleanor M. B.), at Dumblum, Hickory Grove, Prince William County, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, June 1894-May 1898., 2 items. (Folder 6)
      - Letter, 24 June 1894. (Folder 6)
      - Letter, 12 May 1898. (Folder 6)
    - Letters from Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell, mother of Benjamin S. Ewell, March 1831-November 1858., 64 items. (Folder 6-7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin Ewell, at West Point, New York. Postmarked Centreville, [Fairfax County], Virginia, 13-26 March 1831. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at West Point, New York. Postmarked Buckland, Prince William County, 12 May 1832. (Folder 6)
        Rebecca Ewell to her brother, Benjamin S. Ewell. (On same sheet.) Elizabeth S. Ewell to her brother, Benjamin S. Ewell. (On same sheet.)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Rebecca Stoddert, at Bladensburgh, Prince George's County, Maryland. Postmarked Greenwich, Prince William County, Virginia, 12 April 1835. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to her daughter, Rebecca L. Ewell, at Bladensburgh, Maryland. Postmarked Greenwich, Virginia, 10 March 1836. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania. Postmarked Greenwich, Virginia, 24 December 1836. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth), at Stony Lonesome, [Prince William County], to Benjamin Stoddert Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania, 24 January 1837. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania. Postmarked Brentsville, Prince William County, Virginia, 11 July 1837. (Folder 6)
        Postscript signed: R. L. E.
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania. Postmarked Buckland, Prince William County, 24 July 1838. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania. Postmarked Buckland, 13 September 1838. (Folder 6)
        The letter includes a check drawn by Elizabeth Ewell payable to Benjamin S. Ewell. 18 September 1838.
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania. Postmarked Brentsville, Prince William County, Virginia, 8 December 1836. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin Stoddert Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania. Postmarked Buckland, 10 March 1839. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Hampden Sidney, Prince Edward County, Virginia, 26 October 1839. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to B. S. Ewell, at Prince Edward Court House, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, December 1839-March 1840., 2 items. (Folder 6)
        - Letter, 12 December 1839. (Folder 6)
        - Letter, 15 March 1840. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to her daughter, Rebecca L. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C. Postmarked Millford Mills, [Prince William County], Virginia, November 1840., 2 items. (Folder 6)
        - Letter, 7 November 1840. (Folder 6)
          Postscript by A. Gantt.
        - Letter, 21 November 1840. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin Stoddert Ewell, at Prince Edward Court House, Virginia. Postmarked Millford Mills, Virginia, 13 April 1841. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to William Stoddert, at Prince Edward Court House, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, 10 January 1842. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin Stoddert Ewell, at Prince Edward Court House. Postmarked Buckland, 23 April 1842. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Prince Edward Court House. Postmarked Buckland, 27 November 1842. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to her daughter, Rebecca L. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C. Postmarked Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia, 3 December 1842. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Rebecca L. Ewell, January 1843. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Prince Edward Court House, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, 26 November 1843. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C. Postmarked Buckland, 16 June 1845. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Prince Edward Court House, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, 1 January 1846. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Prince Edward Court House, Virginia. Postmarked Millford Mills, Prince William County, Virginia, 29 January 1846. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Prince Edward Court House, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, 19 August 1846. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Lexington, Rockbridge County, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, October 1846-March 1848., 5 items. (Folder 6)
        - Letter, 5 October 1846. (Folder 6)
        - Letter, 27 October 1846. (Folder 6)
        - Letter, 13 September 1847. (Folder 6)
        - Letter, 24 January 1848. (Folder 6)
        - Letter, 5 March 1848. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to her son, William Stoddert, 3 July 1848. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, 14 October 1848. (Folder 6)
        Postscript by R. L. Ewell.
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, 5 December 1848. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, Virginia, 18 November 1849. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Lexington, Virginia. Postmarked Buckland, Virginia, 20 November 1849. (Folder 6)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Mrs. Rebecca Hubbard, 16 January 1850. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to her daughter, Rebecca Ewell, 4 February 1850. (Folder 7)
        Ewell (Elizabeth) to her daughter, Elizabeth Ewell. (On same sheet.)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 7 February 1850. (Folder 7)
        An unsigned, undated letter appears on the same sheet.
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, 11 March 1850. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Capt. Richard S. Ewell, at Richmond, Virginia. Postmarked Nashville, Tennessee, 12 June 1850. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Rebecca Ewell, 30 October 1851. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to her son, Benjamin Stoddert Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia. Postmarked Bristoe [Bristow] Station, Prince William County, Virginia, 19 October 1852. (Folder 7)
        Elizabeth S. Ewell, to her father, Benjamin S. Ewell. (On same sheet.)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to her son, William Stoddert, June-July 1856., 2 items. (Folder 7)
        - Letter, 28 June 1856. (Folder 7)
        - Letter, 6 July 1856. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to William Stoddert, 4 September 1856. (Folder 7)
        Hattie Turner to her cousin, William Stoddert. (On same sheet.)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Rebecca Ewell, 22 October 1856. (Folder 7)
        A. L. Prout to Rebecca Ewell. (On same sheet.)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to William Stoddert, January-July 1857., 2 items. (Folder 7)
        - Letter, 11 January 1857. (Folder 7)
        - Letter, 8 July 1857. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Rebecca Ewell, 11 July 1857. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to William Stoddert, August-December 1857., 2 items. (Folder 7)
        - Letter, 7 August 1857. (Folder 7)
        - Letter, 21 December 1857. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to her son, Richard Ewell, 15 January 1858. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to William Stoddert, June 1858., 2 items. (Folder 7)
        - Letter, 8 June 1858. (Folder 7)
        - Letter, 17 June 1858. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Richard Ewell, 9 July 1858. (Folder 7)
        (See William and Mary Papers, Folder 17, Item 3.)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to William Stoddert, July-September 1858., 3 items. (Folder 7)
        - Letter, 11 July 1858. (Folder 7)
        - Letter, 22 July 1858. (Folder 7)
        - Letter, 14 September 1858. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Rebecca Ewell, 16 September 1858. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to her granddaughter, Elizabeth Ewell, 1 November 1858. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to William Stoddert, 18 November 1858. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to B. S. Ewell, at Lexington, Rockbridge County, Virginia, undated., Two undated letters. One mutilated. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin Stoddert Ewell, at West Point, New York, undated., Two undated letters. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at West Point, New York. Postmarked Greenwich, Prince William County, Virginia. (Folder 7)
        Postscript by R. Stoddert.
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to B. Stoddert Ewell, at West Point, New York. Postmarked Centreville, Fairfax County, Virginia. (Folder 7)
        Rebecca Ewell to Benjamin Ewell. (On same sheet.)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania. Postmarked Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Benjamin S. Ewell, undated., Two undated letters. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Rebecca Ewell, undated., Two undated letters. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Bladensburgh, Prince George's County, Maryland. Postmarked Buckland., Two letters. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Bladensburgh, Maryland. Postmarked Washington, D.C. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Bladensburgh, Prince George's County, Maryland. Postmarked Buckland. (Folder 7)
        Elizabeth S. Ewell to her sister, Rebecca L. Ewell. (On same sheet.)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Washington, D.C. Postmarked Buckland., Two items. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth), at Hayes, to Rebecca Lowndes Ewell, at Centreville, Fairfax County, Virginia. Postmarked Georgetown, D.C. (Folder 7)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth), at Stony Lonesome, Prince William County, to Rebecca L. Ewell, at George-Town, D.C. (Folder 7)
    - Letters from Elizabeth S. Ewell, sister of Benjamin S. Ewell, May 1834-July 1894., 40 items. (Folder 8)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth S.) to her sister, Rebecca L. Ewell, at Bladensburgh, Maryland. Postmarked Greenwich, Prince William County, Virginia, May 1834. (Folder 8)
        An unsigned letter to Nancy [ ? ]. (On same sheet.)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth S.) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at West Point, New York. Postmarked Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia, 16 September 1834. (Folder 8)
        The musical score of a cotillion and a postscript by her mother, Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell, appear on the same sheet.
      - Ewell (Elizabeth S.) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Bladensburgh, Prince George's County, Maryland. Postmarked Greenwich, Virginia, 7 September 1835. (Folder 8)
        Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell to Nancy [ ? ]. (On same sheet.)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth S.) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania. Postmarked Haymarket, Prince William County, Virginia, 7 September 1837. (Folder 8)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth S.) to Benjamin S. Ewell, at York, Pennsylvania. Postmarked Buckland, 15 January 1838. (Folder 8)
        Postscript by Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell.
      - Ewell (Elizabeth S.) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Bladensburgh, Prince George's County, Maryland. Postmarked Buckland, 1 February 1838. (Folder 8)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth S.) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Bladensburgh, Prince George's County, Maryland. Postmarked Brentsville, Prince William County, Virginia, 11 April 1838. (Folder 8)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth S.) to her aunt, [ ? ], 3 May 1838. (Folder 8)
        Ewell (Elizabeth S.) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Bladensburgh, Prince George's County, Maryland. Postmarked Buckland. 21 May 1838. (On same sheet.)
      - Ewell (Elizabeth S.) to Rebecca Ewell. Postmarked Buckland, 19 July 1838. (Folder 8)
        The letter is directed to Mrs. Ann Gantt, at Red Sulphur Springs, Monroe County, Virginia.
      - Ewell (Elizabeth S.) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia. Postmarked Washington, D.C., 14 February 1839. (Folder 8)